<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Otherstuffs on Alfie Pates</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Otherstuffs on Alfie Pates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:17:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AlotBot Reference Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/alotbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:17:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/alotbot/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hey! Here&amp;rsquo;s the (unofficial) reference for &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/SN4T14/AlotBot&#34;&gt;SN4T14&amp;rsquo;s AlotBot&lt;/a&gt;, the resident IRC bot of #DataHoarder on Freenode.  AlotBot was originally meant to be a joke, to provide tongue-in-cheek corrections when users typed &amp;ldquo;alot&amp;rdquo; and meant &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;. From there, it spiralled out into the wonderfully useful tool you use today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/crsoi5U.png&#34;&gt;Testing this bot was real fun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;plugins:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Plugins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alot-js-allot-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;alot.js&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;allot.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corrects users who type &amp;lsquo;alot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;allot&amp;rsquo; when they mean &amp;lsquo;a lot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;### Usage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message containing the word &amp;lsquo;alot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;allot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: i just ate alot of food
  AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;alot&amp;quot; is not a word! &amp;quot;a lot&amp;quot; is the correct term!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: there sure are allot of spelling mistakes in this channel
  AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;allot&amp;quot; is not a word! &amp;quot;a lot&amp;quot; is the correct term!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;xbmc-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;xbmc.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes users aware that the XBMC project is now called Kodi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message containing the word &amp;lsquo;XBMC&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: my HTPC runs XBMC
   AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;XBMC&amp;quot; is the old name! It&#39;s now called &amp;quot;Kodi&amp;quot;!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;zol-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zol.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points users towards &lt;a href=&#34;http://sn4t14.com/zol/&#34;&gt;SN4T14&amp;rsquo;s ZFS on Linux stability rant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage-1:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message starting with &amp;lsquo;AlotBot&amp;rsquo; and containing either &amp;lsquo;ZOL&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;ZFS on Linux&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, tell me about ZOL
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://sn4t14.com/zol/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, why is ZFS on Linux unstable?
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://sn4t14.com/zol/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;datahoarderwiki-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;datahoarderWiki.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fetches a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/wiki&#34;&gt;/r/DataHoarder wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage-2:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message starting with &amp;lsquo;AlotBot&amp;rsquo; and containing the phrase &amp;lsquo;datahoarder wiki&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, where&#39;s the datahoarder wiki at?
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://reddit.com/r/datahoarder/wiki
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRC Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/irc-code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 21:53:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/irc-code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be friendly and patient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be welcoming&lt;/strong&gt;: We strive to be a community that welcomes and supports people of all backgrounds and identities. This includes, but is not limited to members of any race, ethnicity, culture, national origin, colour, immigration status, social and economic class, educational level, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, age, size, family status, political belief, religion, and mental and physical ability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be considerate&lt;/strong&gt;: Your work will be used by other people, and you in turn will depend on the work of others. Any decision you take will affect users and colleagues, and you should take those consequences into account when making decisions. Remember that we&amp;rsquo;re a world-wide community, so you might not be communicating in someone else&amp;rsquo;s primary language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be respectful&lt;/strong&gt;:  Not all of us will agree all the time, but disagreement is no excuse for poor behavior and poor manners. We might all experience some frustration now and then, but we cannot allow that frustration to turn into a personal attack. It’s important to remember that a community where people feel uncomfortable or threatened is not a productive one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful in the words that we choose&lt;/strong&gt;: we are a community of professionals, and we conduct ourselves professionally. Be kind to others. Do not insult or put down other participants. Harassment and other exclusionary behavior aren&amp;rsquo;t acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to understand why we disagree&lt;/strong&gt;: Disagreements, both social and technical, happen all the time. It is important that we resolve disagreements and differing views constructively. Remember that we’re different. The strength of our community comes from its diversity, people from a wide range of backgrounds. Different people have different perspectives on issues. Being unable to understand why someone holds a viewpoint doesn’t mean that they’re wrong. Don’t forget that it is human to err and blaming each other doesn’t get us anywhere. Instead, focus on helping to resolve issues and learning from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;definitions:c3628244aba51e2f9505f07548a46058&#34;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harassment includes, but is not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offensive comments related to gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, mental illness, neuro(a)typicality, physical appearance, body size, race, age, regional discrimination, political or religious affiliation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unwelcome comments regarding a person’s lifestyle choices and practices, including those related to food, health, parenting, drugs, and employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate misgendering. This includes deadnaming or persistently using a pronoun that does not correctly reflect a person&amp;rsquo;s gender identity. You must address people by the name they give you when not addressing them by their username or handle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulated physical contact (eg, textual descriptions like “*hug*” or “*backrub*”) without consent or after a request to stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threats of violence, both physical and psychological&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incitement of violence towards any individual, including encouraging a person to commit suicide or to engage in self-harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate intimidation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harassing photography or recording, including logging online activity for harassment purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustained disruption of discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unwelcome sexual attention, including gratuitous or off-topic sexual images or behaviour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pattern of inappropriate social contact, such as requesting/assuming inappropriate levels of intimacy with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued one-on-one communication after requests to cease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate “outing” of any aspect of a person’s identity without their consent except as necessary to protect others from intentional abuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication of non-harassing private communication without reasonable justification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This code of conduct was loosely based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://todogroup.org/opencodeofconduct/&#34;&gt;TODO Group Open Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>