<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alfie Pates</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alfie Pates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 10:22:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll your own Mail Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/diy-mail-server-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 10:22:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/diy-mail-server-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used outlook.com for my personal e-mail. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been super satisfied with it, but hey, it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; worked. Recently I realised that the outlook.com spam filter had been dropping e-mails before they even reached my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlotBot Reference Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/alotbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:17:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/alotbot/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hey! Here&amp;rsquo;s the (unofficial) reference for &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/SN4T14/AlotBot&#34;&gt;SN4T14&amp;rsquo;s AlotBot&lt;/a&gt;, the resident IRC bot of #DataHoarder on Freenode.  AlotBot was originally meant to be a joke, to provide tongue-in-cheek corrections when users typed &amp;ldquo;alot&amp;rdquo; and meant &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;. From there, it spiralled out into the wonderfully useful tool you use today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/crsoi5U.png&#34;&gt;Testing this bot was real fun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;plugins:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Plugins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alot-js-allot-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;alot.js&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;allot.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corrects users who type &amp;lsquo;alot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;allot&amp;rsquo; when they mean &amp;lsquo;a lot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;### Usage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message containing the word &amp;lsquo;alot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;allot&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: i just ate alot of food
  AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;alot&amp;quot; is not a word! &amp;quot;a lot&amp;quot; is the correct term!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: there sure are allot of spelling mistakes in this channel
  AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;allot&amp;quot; is not a word! &amp;quot;a lot&amp;quot; is the correct term!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;xbmc-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;xbmc.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes users aware that the XBMC project is now called Kodi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message containing the word &amp;lsquo;XBMC&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: my HTPC runs XBMC
   AlotBot: Oi! alfiepates! &amp;quot;XBMC&amp;quot; is the old name! It&#39;s now called &amp;quot;Kodi&amp;quot;!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;zol-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;zol.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points users towards &lt;a href=&#34;http://sn4t14.com/zol/&#34;&gt;SN4T14&amp;rsquo;s ZFS on Linux stability rant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage-1:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message starting with &amp;lsquo;AlotBot&amp;rsquo; and containing either &amp;lsquo;ZOL&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;ZFS on Linux&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, tell me about ZOL
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://sn4t14.com/zol/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, why is ZFS on Linux unstable?
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://sn4t14.com/zol/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;datahoarderwiki-js:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;datahoarderWiki.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fetches a link to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/DataHoarder/wiki&#34;&gt;/r/DataHoarder wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage-2:7a7d59b9e798081b0d55d9d01877bf20&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send a message starting with &amp;lsquo;AlotBot&amp;rsquo; and containing the phrase &amp;lsquo;datahoarder wiki&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfiepates: AlotBot, where&#39;s the datahoarder wiki at?
   AlotBot: Here you go: http://reddit.com/r/datahoarder/wiki
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRC Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/irc-code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 21:53:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/otherstuff/irc-code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be friendly and patient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be welcoming&lt;/strong&gt;: We strive to be a community that welcomes and supports people of all backgrounds and identities. This includes, but is not limited to members of any race, ethnicity, culture, national origin, colour, immigration status, social and economic class, educational level, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, age, size, family status, political belief, religion, and mental and physical ability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be considerate&lt;/strong&gt;: Your work will be used by other people, and you in turn will depend on the work of others. Any decision you take will affect users and colleagues, and you should take those consequences into account when making decisions. Remember that we&amp;rsquo;re a world-wide community, so you might not be communicating in someone else&amp;rsquo;s primary language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be respectful&lt;/strong&gt;:  Not all of us will agree all the time, but disagreement is no excuse for poor behavior and poor manners. We might all experience some frustration now and then, but we cannot allow that frustration to turn into a personal attack. It’s important to remember that a community where people feel uncomfortable or threatened is not a productive one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be careful in the words that we choose&lt;/strong&gt;: we are a community of professionals, and we conduct ourselves professionally. Be kind to others. Do not insult or put down other participants. Harassment and other exclusionary behavior aren&amp;rsquo;t acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to understand why we disagree&lt;/strong&gt;: Disagreements, both social and technical, happen all the time. It is important that we resolve disagreements and differing views constructively. Remember that we’re different. The strength of our community comes from its diversity, people from a wide range of backgrounds. Different people have different perspectives on issues. Being unable to understand why someone holds a viewpoint doesn’t mean that they’re wrong. Don’t forget that it is human to err and blaming each other doesn’t get us anywhere. Instead, focus on helping to resolve issues and learning from mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;definitions:c3628244aba51e2f9505f07548a46058&#34;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harassment includes, but is not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offensive comments related to gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, mental illness, neuro(a)typicality, physical appearance, body size, race, age, regional discrimination, political or religious affiliation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unwelcome comments regarding a person’s lifestyle choices and practices, including those related to food, health, parenting, drugs, and employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate misgendering. This includes deadnaming or persistently using a pronoun that does not correctly reflect a person&amp;rsquo;s gender identity. You must address people by the name they give you when not addressing them by their username or handle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulated physical contact (eg, textual descriptions like “*hug*” or “*backrub*”) without consent or after a request to stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threats of violence, both physical and psychological&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incitement of violence towards any individual, including encouraging a person to commit suicide or to engage in self-harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate intimidation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harassing photography or recording, including logging online activity for harassment purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustained disruption of discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unwelcome sexual attention, including gratuitous or off-topic sexual images or behaviour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pattern of inappropriate social contact, such as requesting/assuming inappropriate levels of intimacy with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued one-on-one communication after requests to cease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliberate “outing” of any aspect of a person’s identity without their consent except as necessary to protect others from intentional abuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publication of non-harassing private communication without reasonable justification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This code of conduct was loosely based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://todogroup.org/opencodeofconduct/&#34;&gt;TODO Group Open Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Piano Tuning, Pt1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/pianotuning1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 20:48:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/pianotuning1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/pianotuning/piano1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Piano&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, my grandmother has had this great big upright piano in her living room. It&amp;rsquo;s always been terribly out of tune, so since I&amp;rsquo;m staying with her this week I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at it. And because I have a nice shiny new blog, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m gonna end up blogging about it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not a professional piano tuner&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not even an amateur piano tuner, I&amp;rsquo;m a guy who has an old piano and fancied trying his hand at tuning it. Tuning your own piano could potentially damage the instrument, I&amp;rsquo;m not responsible for any damage that you may inflict on your piano. If you&amp;rsquo;re a professional piano tuner then you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to stay away from this article too, it might upset you a little.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I know fuck all about tuning pianos, the first thing to do was actually figure out how the hell a piano is tuned. I knew it was somewhat like tuning a guitar - the strings are tensioned by tuning pegs, tighten or loosen the tuning pegs to raise or lower the pitch - and I knew you needed a tuning lever to adjust the tuning pegs. So, I started by trying to find exactly what kind of tuning lever I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I discovered while researching piano tuning is that professional piano tuners &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t like DIYers. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s understandable since having an upright like my grandmothers&amp;rsquo; professionally tuned can cost betwen £60 and £90 twice a year, not an insignificant amount of money. I also learned a lot about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; exactly pianos go out of tune: pianos are made of wood, which contracts and expands as the humidity and temperature changes. This causes the strings to slowly loosen over time, which causes the piano to lose it&amp;rsquo;s tuning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After half an hour of googling and reading, I discovered that piano tuning pegs come in many different sizes. Or at least, they kinda do. Or they don&amp;rsquo;t, depending on where you look. Or they do but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Or there may be many sizes on one piano. Or maybe nobody can seem to agree on what size the tuning pegs actually are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On pretty much any piano made in the last 100 years or so, the tuning pegs have a square, tapered profile. Most piano tuning lever tips have an eight-pointed-star-shaped profile, to fit on the end of the tuning peg. It makes sense that the tuning tip should fit right on the tapered tip&amp;hellip; but apparently not. It turns out that there are five sizes of tuning tips, to fit five different sizes of tuning pegs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tip Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Peg Diameter&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.272&amp;rdquo; / 6.91mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.276&amp;rdquo; / 7.01mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.282&amp;rdquo; / 7.16mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.286&amp;rdquo; / 7.26mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.291&amp;rdquo; / 7.39mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;#5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(.296&amp;rdquo; / 7.52mm) dia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how close the sizes are? Yeah, me too. The different sizes are designed to accommodate subtle variations in the sizes of the tuning pegs. A few sources advised that I bought each size, and used the one that fit most snugly on each peg. Then again, these places also sold the damn things so it was in their interest to make me buy the lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of reading, the general consensus seemed to be that a #2 tuning lever should be adequate for DIY tuning. With that information in hand, I finally set out to actually purchase a tuning lever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, being an internet user, the first place I looked was Amazon. As it turns out, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/s/?&amp;amp;field-keywords=piano+tuning+lever&#34;&gt;there are a surprising number of piano tuning levers for sale on Amazon UK&lt;/a&gt;, some for very cheap indeed. One lever in particular that caught my eye was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B000XUURXC/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; from Konig &amp;amp; Meyer, makers of industry standard microphone stands and the wonderful Spider series of keyboard stands. I&amp;rsquo;d been warned against inexpensive tuning levers during my research, but I have faith in the K&amp;amp;M brand, so I decided to take the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to a tuning lever, I also needed some mutes, which are used to silence the individual strings to be tuned, since each piano key has multiple strings. I went with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B00CQEK1Q6&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; kit, which contains four mutes and a temperament strip. This bought my final total to £31.78, a fairly respectable amount to spend on an experiment such as this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, buy the time the tools arrived I&amp;rsquo;d have left my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s house, so the next installment of this post will have to wait until I have access to the piano again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Packs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 21:24:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/samples/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/newsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 02:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/newsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I finally got round to setting up a proper website for myself. I toyed with the idea of writing something from scratch for a while using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com&#34;&gt;bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://getskeleton.com&#34;&gt;skeleton&lt;/a&gt; until I was introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderfully simple static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it&amp;rsquo;s most basic form, a static site generator takes content in some kind of markup language, applies a theme, and renders the content to HTML. You can then drop this HTML on a lightweight webserver (I use thttpd) for a very low-footprint website. Static site generators combine the ease of using a CMS with the speed and efficiency of pure static HTML. I chose &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; in particular due to it&amp;rsquo;s super short build times, support of Markdown and it&amp;rsquo;s built-in webserver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now used &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; for a few days to set up this site, I can say I&amp;rsquo;m 100% on board with the whole concept. I know Markdown pretty much inside out which makes writing new content a breeze and using static HTML as opposed to a dynamic CMS does wonders for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://wpvulndb.com&#34;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; and page load times. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it yet, but I should hopefully be able to setup hugo in a git recieve hook, so that all I need to do in order to update the site is run a &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; from my &lt;code&gt;~/src/alfiepates.me&lt;/code&gt; directory and have the server automatically build the new website. Expect more blog posts about it in the future, as I figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion? Hugo is fucking awesome, you should totally check it out next time you need a static site for a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the current (as of 18-07-2015) homebrew formula for &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t the latest version, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a lot of themes. In the mean time, grab the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;binary&lt;/a&gt; and chuck it in your &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 02:21:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Alfie. I&amp;rsquo;m an audio engineer, hobbyist developer and general internet moron. This is my website, where I blog about music technology, computers, and the occasional bit of programming. It&amp;rsquo;s more written as a tool for me to collect my thoughts than a blog, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d publish it anyway incase my inane ramblings can be of aid to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/license/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-license:53e892b8b41cc4caece1cfd5ef21d6e7&#34;&gt;Content license&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All non-code content is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;, except where explicitly noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-license:53e892b8b41cc4caece1cfd5ef21d6e7&#34;&gt;Code license&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All source code files and snippets found on this blog, unless otherwise explicitly noted, are licensed under the terms below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;Copyright 2015 Alfie Pates

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &amp;quot;License&amp;quot;);
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an &amp;quot;AS IS&amp;quot; BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>