<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alfie Pates</title>
    <link>http://alfiepates.me/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alfie Pates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 02:51:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://alfiepates.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site</title>
      <link>http://alfiepates.me/post/newsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 02:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alfiepates.me/post/newsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I finally got round to setting up a proper website for myself. I toyed with the idea of writing something from scratch for a while using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com&#34;&gt;bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://getskeleton.com&#34;&gt;skeleton&lt;/a&gt; until I was introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderfully simple static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it&amp;rsquo;s most basic form, a static site generator takes content in some kind of markup language, applies a theme, and renders the content to HTML. You can then drop this HTML on a lightweight webserver (I use thttpd) for a very low-footprint website. Static site generators combine the ease of using a CMS with the speed and efficiency of pure static HTML. I chose &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; in particular due to it&amp;rsquo;s super short build times, support of Markdown and it&amp;rsquo;s built-in webserver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now used &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; for a few days to set up this site, I can say I&amp;rsquo;m 100% on board with the whole concept. I know Markdown pretty much inside out which makes writing new content a breeze and using static HTML as opposed to a dynamic CMS does wonders for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://wpvulndb.com&#34;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; and page load times. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it yet, but I should hopefully be able to setup hugo in a git recieve hook, so that all I need to do in order to update the site is run a &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; from my &lt;code&gt;~/src/alfiepates.me&lt;/code&gt; directory and have the server automatically build the new website. Expect more blog posts about it in the future, as I figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion? Hugo is fucking awesome, you should totally check it out next time you need a static site for a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the current (as of 18-07-2015) homebrew formula for &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t the latest version, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a lot of themes. In the mean time, grab the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;binary&lt;/a&gt; and chuck it in your &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>